ALIMAZOYA DAVID

CONTACT DETAILS



LINKS



SKILLS

Responsive web design	6 years
JavaScript	7 years
Typescript	5 years
React/Next	5 years
Node/Nest	5 years
Git	6 years
GraphQL	3 years
React Native	3 years
Postgres	5 years
Tailwind CSS	5 years
CSS	6 years
Blockchain systems	3 years

SUMMARY

I am an experienced Software Developer with over 6 years of experience in the industry. I specialize in NextJS/React development and have extensive knowledge of API integration. I have a passion for software improvement and experience working in fast pace environments. My robust design and architectural experience, combined with my software testing and release management skills, make me a perfect fit for the position.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer,, eTranzact plc, Lagos.

April 2018 - Present

- Developed and maintained web applications using React, Next JS, Node, and CI/CD
- Collaborated with team members to design, develop, and maintain software products
- Participated in code reviews and ensured code quality and performance
- Identified and fixed bugs and performance issues
- Worked with the team to continuously improve the development process and methodology

Frontend Developer, ComradeNG, Lagos.

January 2015 - March 2018

- Designed and implemented user interfaces for web applications using HTML, CSS, and
- JavaScript.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to ensure seamless integration between front-end
- and back-end systems.
- Developed and maintained responsive web applications that helped increase user
- engagement and retention.
- Improved website performance by optimizing the code, reducing page load time, and
- improving overall user experience.
- Worked on various retail and e-commerce projects, collaborating with cross-functional
- teams to ensure the successful implementation of projects.
- Developed and maintained web applications using React.js and i18next
- Designed and implemented solutions for non-standard problems
- Decomposed tasks into logical blocks according to best practices such as OOP, SOLID, Design
- Patterns, Agile Methodologies, and Clean Code
- Documented code and communicate with other team members

EDUCATION

University of Benin

November 2011 - August 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

CERTIFICATION

Enterprise Design Thinking, IBM

December 2015

SKILLS

- Proficient in Next JS, Node, and CI/CD
- Strong problem-solving and analytical skills
- Excellent communication and collaboration skills
- Experience working in an Agile development environment
- Familiarity with software development tools and technologies, such as Git, Jira, and AWS